Guide to the Franklin Toker Papers, 1964-2017 UA.90.F108
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Florence Duomo Project, 1970-2017; IV.
  - When Stones Speak: The Florence Duomo Excavations in the Light of History, 2017; 4.
    These files contain three drafts of the fourth and final book of the Florence Duomo Project.
    - When Stones Speak Rough Draft #1 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - When Stones Speak Rough Draft #2 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - When Stones Speak Rough Drafts (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Other Publications, 5.
    This subseries is a collection of preliminary research drafts and articles pertaining to a variety of themes from the Florence Duomo Project books. Much of the information in these publications was either built upon or used as research for Dr. Toker's books.
    - Appendixes (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - The Apse and Towers Draft (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - A Baptismal Basin in Florence Draft (Box 28, Folder 17-18)
    - Bibliographies (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - Cathedral and City in Medieval Florence Rough Drafts (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Cradle of Faith Article Drafts (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Dumos Ecclesiae Draft (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Earliest Archaeological Evidence Draft (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Earliest Christians in Florence Drafts (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Excavations Below S. Maria Del Fiore Volume II: Rough Drafts (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Excavations Below S. Maria Del Fiore Volume VI: Rough Drafts (Box 29, Folder 6-7)
    - Excavations in Florence Volume One Rough Drafts (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - The Existing Baptistery Drafts (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Figure List for Florence Book (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - The First Baptistery in Florence Draft (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - I Dipinti Di Santa Reparata Draft (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Mores Articles and Research (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - The Planning Behind Roman Florence Draft (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Rebuilding the Nave Draft (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Ritus in Ecclesia Servandi Drafts (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Roman Metrical Planning for Houses Draft (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Santa Reparata Excavations and Study of the Ancient Cathedral Thesis Rough Drafts (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Santa Reparata: Excavation History Rough Draft (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Santa Reparata Workshop (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Various Article Drafts (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Research, 1970-2017; 6.
    These files contain the various research articles, photographs, architectural drawings, and notes used to produce the Florence Duomo Project books. The files have maintained their original titles and are arranged alphabetically.
    - Active Reports, 2008-2010 (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - Active Reports, 2008-2010 (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
    - Apse and Towers Research (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Archaeology Record (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Articles on Florence Research (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Baptistry Excavations (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Baptistry Photos (Box 30, Folder 7-8)
    - Bibliography and Duomo Research (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Buerger Finds (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Canonry Research (Box 30, Folder 11-13)
    - Cap 1 Illustrations (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Carolingian Church Blueprints and Photos (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Carolingian, Romanesque, and Comparisons SRII Comparatives (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Carolingian, Romanesque, and Comparisons SRII Comparatives (Box 31, Folder 1-2)
    - Comparative Tomb Slabs (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - De Prima Dominica De Adventvi (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Drawing and Photo List (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - The Duomo Project Notes and Research (Box 31, Folder 6-7)
    - Duomo Research and Correspondence (Box 31, Folder 8-9)
    - Early Christian Blueprints (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Early Christian Church Research (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Early Medieval Liturgical Research (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Excavation Chronology (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Façade Fragments (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Fifth Floor Roman Domus (Box 31, Folder 15-16)
    - Floors by Chronology (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Floor 1: Duomo Pavement (Box 31, Folder 18-19)
    - Floor 3 Romanesque Research (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Florence Architecture Photos and Blueprints (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Florence Cathedral Symposia (Box 32, Folder 2-3)
    - Florence Churches Blueprints and Photos (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Florence Church Photo Prints and Research (Box 32, Folder 5-6)
    - Fresco Information (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Gothic Architecture and Tombs (Box 32, Folder 8-10)
    - Introduction to Ritual Volume (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Latin Inscriptions and Graffiti (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Library of Florence Research (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Medici Tombs and Research (Box 32, Folder 14-15)
    - Medieval Ceramics and Other Finds (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Medieval Ceramics and Other Finds (Box 33, Folder 1-4)
    - Medieval Coins, Glass, Ceramics, and Metal Work (Box 33, Folder 5-8)
    - Moreni Articles (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Mural Painting Photos (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Negatives of Santa Reparata Photos (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - On Holy Ground Research Articles (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Other Excavation Reports and Research (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Photos of Archaeological Finds (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Processional Route Information in and Around Florence (Box 33, Folder 15-16)
    - Processional Route Information in and Around Florence (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Poussin Research (Box 34, Folder 2-3)
    - Renaissance/Gothic floors and Structures Photos (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Research Images (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Research Segments (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Rituality in Santa Reparata (Box 34, Folder 7-8)
    - Ritus Articles and Research (Box 34, Folder 9-10)
    - Ritus Form Contents and Partial Translations (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Ritus in Ecclesia Servandi Research and Notes (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Ritus Microfilm (Box 34, Folder 13-14)
    - Roman Art Analysis (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Roman Coin Research (Box 34, Folder 16-17)
    - Roman Decorations and Ceramics (Box 35, Folder 1-2)
    - Roman Photos (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Romanesque Blueprints (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Romanesque Church Blueprints and Photos (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Santa Maria del Fiore aerial with Baptistery (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Santa Maria del Fiore Research (Box 35, Folder 7-8)
    - Santa Reparata Excavation (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Santa Reparata Historiography (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Santa Reparata Interior Aerial View (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Santa Reparata Photocopies (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Santa Reparata Photos and Workshop, 1995 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Santa Reparata's Neighboring Building Relics (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Special Finds listings and Photographs (Box 35, Folder 15-16)
    - Specialists' Reports and Dig Zone Information (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Specific Architectural Features in Ritus and Mores Especially Altars (Box 35, Folder 18-19)
    - Stratigraphy (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - Stratigraphy drawings and others needed for cat. Vol. Research (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - Stratigraphy drawings and others needed for cat. Vol. Research (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
    - Tacconi and Ritus Readings (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Tomb Research (Box 36, Folder 4-5)
    - Tombs 81 and 46 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Tombs at the Duomo Church (Box 36, Folder 7-9)
    - Topographic Account of Chancel of the Church (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Topographic account of Nave of the Church (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Topographic account of North Aisle of the Church (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Topographic account of North Outside of the Church (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Topographic Account of Parts of the Church (Box 36, Folder 14-15)
    - Topographic Account of South Aisle of the Church (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Topographic Account of South Outside of the Church (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Vannini and Veranica Photo (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - Volume I: Pictorial Evidence (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - Ware and Decorations Found (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1985-2012; 7.
    The correspondence in this subseries pertains to the development and progress of the Florence Duomo Project. Included are letters from people at the University of Pittsburgh, as well as architectural historians and others with interest in the project.
    - Pitt Correspondence, 1985-1990 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Professional Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 37, Folder 3-4)
    - Professional Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Professional Correspondence, 2012 (Box 37, Folder 6-7)
  - Arnolfo di Cambio Research, 1975; 8.
    Florence architect Arnolfo di Cambio designed aspects of the Duomo at the end of the thirteenth century. These research files pertaining to di Cambio's designs and contributions to the Duomo were intended to be used by Dr. Toker for a book on the architect's career.
    - Alfonso Di Cambio the Beginnings of Artistic Identity (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Archeologia Medievale, 1975 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Arnolfo Research (Box 37, Folder 10-15)
    - Arnolfo Research (Box 38, Folder 1-12)
    - Arnolfo Research (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Arte d'Occidente temi e metodi (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Artwork Examples (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Cesta Internation Center of Medieval Art, 1975 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Juan José De Austria Research (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Las Meninas Research (Box 39, Folder 6-9)
    - Maser Italy Research (Box 39, Folder 10-12)
    - Sansedoni Article and Research (Box 39, Folder 13-15)
    - Santa Croce Research (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - Santa Croce Research (Box 40, Folder 1-2)
- Hall of Architecture, V.
  This series consists mostly of photographs and research on the architecture of the casts in the Carnegie Museum of Natural History's Hall of Architecture. This research was used to write a 2013 feasibility study to restore the room and the casts.
  - American Casts (Box 40, Folder 3-4)
  - Architecture Hall: Chicago (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Architecture Hall: Columbia University Casts (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Architecture Hall: Corcoran Gallery Washington D.C. (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Architecture Hall: The Met, New York City (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Architecture Hall: National Institute of Design: New York City (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Architecture Hall: Paris Casts (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Architecture Hall: Philadelphia Museum of Art Casts (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Architecture Hall: Publication (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Architecture Hall: Queens Museum Casts (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Architecture Hall Research and Correspondence (Box 40, Folder 14-15)
  - Architecture Hall: Saint Louis Art Museum Restored Casts (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Architecture Hall: Slater Memorial Art Museum: Norwich, Connecticut (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Architecture Hall: Springfield, Massachusetts (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Architecture Hall: University of California Berkley Casts (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Architecture Hall: Victoria and Albert Cast Court (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - Bibliography (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Carnegie Institute Published Information (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - Carnegie Magazine Article (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - Cast Collection by Specific Museums: Architecture Hall: Boston Museum of Fine Art (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - Cast Collection by Specific Museums: Architecture Hall: Harvard Casts (Box 40, Folder 25)
  - Cast Collection by Specific Museums: Architecture Hall University of Texas (Box 40, Folder 26)
  - Cast Collection by Specific Museums: Kunst Og Museum saernummer (Box 40, Folder 27)
  - Cast Questions (Box 40, Folder 28)
  - Foreign Museums (Box 40, Folder 29)
  - General Archive Information (Box 40, Folder 30)
  - Hall of Architecture, Carnegie Museum of Art by Franklin Toker Paper (Box 40, Folder 31)
  - Hall of Architecture Cast Collection (Box 40, Folder 32)
  - Hall of Architecture Files (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Hall of Architecture Graphics (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Hall of Architecture Photos and Notes (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Hall of Architecture Research (Box 41, Folder 4-7)
  - Hyman Meyers Correspondence (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - John Dennis Research (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Letters Filed Alphabetically (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Letters with Negative Replies (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Making Casts (Box 41, Folder 12-13)
  - MOA Correspondence (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Other Cast Collective (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Pitt Forms for the Hall (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Potential Bibliography (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - Potential Ideas (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - Renaissance Architecture: The Siena Baptismal Font. Siena, Italy (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - Renaissance Architecture: The Tomb of Francais II of Brittany and his wife Marguerite de Foix. Nantes, France (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - Research Photos (Box 41, Folder 21-22)
  - Research Problems (Box 41, Folder 23)
  - Restoration of Room: New York Senate Chambers (Box 41, Folder 24)
- General Research, VI.
  These research files on Pittsburgh topics and ancient synagogues were compiled for unspecified or never completed projects. Included are articles, photographs, and other resources pertaining to architectural topics.
  - Pittsburgh Research, 1.
    This subseries contains research files on specific architects that have made substantial contributions to the Pittsburgh urban landscape, as well as more general information about Pittsburgh history and buildings. Also included are files on projects that had not been published, "Pittsburgh Transformed" and "Lords of Pittsburgh."
    - Bibliography/ Research Method/ Sources in Pittsburgh Architecture (Box 41, Folder 25-26)
    - Future Pittsburgh Book: Pittsburgh Transformed (Box 42, Folder 1-4)
    - Hornbostel Research (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Images of Pittsburgh in Art and Photos (Box 42, Folder 6-7)
    - Images of Pittsburgh in Graphics (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Images of Pittsburgh in Writing (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Lords of Pittsburgh Unwritten Book (Box 42, Folder 10-12)
    - Pittsburgh Architects Pre-1970s (Box 42, Folder 13-14)
    - Pittsburgh Architects Post-1970s (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - Pittsburgh Architects Post-1970s (Box 43, Folder 1-2)
    - Pittsburgh Architecture by Type (Box 43, Folder 3-6)
    - Pittsburgh History (Box 43, Folder 7-9)
    - Pittsburgh History: Social/ Cultural/ Political (Box 43, Folder 10-11)
    - Pittsburgh Research (Box 43, Folder 12-14)
    - Pittsburgh Research: Allegheny County Courthouse (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - Pittsburgh Research: Allegheny County Courthouse (Box 44, Folder 1-4)
    - Pittsburgh Topography and Maps (Box 44, Folder 5-6)
    - Pittsburgh Urbanism and Neighborhoods (Box 44, Folder 7-9)
    - PPG Place, Styles in Pittsburgh, and Miscellaneous Building and Information (Box 44, Folder 10-11)
    - Richardson, Henry H. Research (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Sullivan, Louis Research (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Toker Minor Articles on Pittsburgh, "Lords of Pittsburgh" Project (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - Toker Minor Articles on Pittsburgh, "Lords of Pittsburgh" Project (Box 45, Folder 1-2)
  - Synagogue Research, 2.
    This subseries contains Dr. Toker's research on ancient Jewish architecture and synagogues. While the intent of the research is not specified, it is likely that some of this material was used for his proposed design of the Israel Heritage Nationality Room in the Cathedral of Learning at the University of Pittsburgh.
    - Ancient Jewish Architecture Research and Notes (Box 45, Folder 3-5)
    - Early Jewish Research (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Early Jewish Synagogue Research (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Synagogue Article (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Synagogues Article and Research (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Synagogue Illustrations (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Synagogue Lecture (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Synagogue Summaries (Box 45, Folder 12)
- Course Material, 1974-2016; VII.
  This series pertains to numerous lectures and seminars given by Dr. Toker over the course of his career at the University of Pittsburgh and Carnegie Mellon University. Topics include Architecture in the Nineteenth Century; Gothic Architecture in Northern Europe; Introduction to the History of Art; and the Romanesque Seminar, among others. Included are source books of articles, lecture notes, syllabi, and research for the courses.
  - American Architecture Civil War to Present, 1997 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - American Architecture From Chicago to Las Vegas Class Information, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - American Architecture: Origins to Civil War Class Information, 1982-1999 (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Archaic Seminar (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - The Architect in History Class Information, 1977 (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Architecture and Urbanism of the Pittsburgh Region Booklet (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - Architecture and Urbanism of the Pittsburgh Region Class Information, 1981-2000 (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Architecture and Urbanism of Pittsburgh Course Materials, 1998-2007 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Architecture Hall Lectures (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Architecture in the Age of Jefferson Class Information, 1981 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Architecture in the High Renaissance Class Information, 1983 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Architecture in the Nineteenth Century Class Information, 1977-1980 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Architecture of H.H. Richardson Seminar, 1976 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Architecture of the Renaissance in Italy Class Information, 1982 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Building a Gothic Cathedral Seminar, 1976 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Cathedral and City in the Middle Ages Class Information, 1981-1989 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - A Celebration of Pittsburgh Industry Class Information, 1978 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Chicago in the Age of Sullivan Class Information, 1976 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Class Emails, Syllabi, and Course Materials (Box 46, Folder 12-13)
  - Class Midterms and Quizzes (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Early American Architecture Class Notes (Box 46, Folder 15-17)
  - Early American Architecture Course Materials Booklet (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - Early Christian and Byzantine Architecture Class Information, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - Early Renaissance Class Notes (Box 46, Folder 20-22)
  - Egyptian Architecture Class Notes (Box 46, Folder 23)
  - Fallingwater Seminar, 1999 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Gothic Architecture and Urbanism Class Information, 1975 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Gothic Architecture in Northern Europe Class Information, 1979 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Gothic Seminar (Box 47, Folder 4-5)
  - Greek Seminar (Box 47, Folder 6-7)
  - High Renaissance Course Materials (Box 47, Folder 8-10)
  - Historic Oakland Scavenger Hunt, 1984 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - History of Architectural Theory Class Information, 1988-1989 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - History of Western Architecture Class Information, 1998-2000 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - History of Western Architecture Sourcebook, Fall 1997 (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - History of Western Architecture Sourcebook, Fall 1998 (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - History of Western Architecture Sourcebook, Fall 1999 (Box 47, Folder 16-17)
  - History of Western Architecture Sourcebook, 2006 (Box 47, Folder 18-19)
  - Introduction to Architectural History Course, 1976-1977 (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - Introduction to Architecture Class Information, 1977-1995 (Box 47, Folder 21-22)
  - Introduction to Art Class Information, 1987-1998 (Box 47, Folder 23)
  - Introduction to the History of Art Fine Arts 001 Sourcebook, Fall 1988 (Box 47, Folder 24)
  - Introduction to the History of Art Spring Voyage Sourcebook, 1992 (Box 47, Folder 25)
  - Introduction to the History of Art Sourcebook, Spring 1998 (Box 47, Folder 26)
  - Introduction to the History of Western Art Booklet (Box 48, Folder 1-2)
  - Introduction to the History of World Architecture Source Book, Fall 1993 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Introduction to the History of World Architecture Sourcebook, Fall 1994 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Introduction to the History of World Architecture Sourcebook, Fall 1995 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Introduction to Western Architecture Class Notes (Box 48, Folder 6-9)
  - Introduction to Western Architectural History Sourcebook, Fall 1996 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Introduction to Western Architecture Sourcebook, Fall 2007 (Box 48, Folder 11-12)
  - Introduction to Western Architecture Sourcebook, 2013 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Introduction to Western Architecture Sourcebook, 2015 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Introduction to Western Architecture, Fall 2016 (Box 48, Folder 15-16)
  - Introductory Architecture Course Notes, 1978 (Box 48, Folder 17-18)
  - Latrobe Seminar, 1974 (Box 48, Folder 19)
  - Medieval Architecture Course Materials (Box 48, Folder 20-21)
  - Medieval Architecture in Europe Class Information, 1975 (Box 48, Folder 22)
  - Methods in Architectural History Class Information, 1990-1993 (Box 48, Folder 23)
  - Methods of Research and Scholarship, Spring 1991 (Box 48, Folder 24)
  - Modern Architecture Class Notes (Box 48, Folder 25-26)
  - Modern Architecture Class Notes (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Pittsburgh Architecture Booklet (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Pittsburgh Architecture Course Materials (Box 49, Folder 3-6)
  - Pittsburgh Lectures (Box 49, Folder 7-13)
  - Renaissance Seminar (Box 50, Folder 1-3)
  - Revitalizing the Hall of Architecture Seminar, 1983 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Revival Architecture in America Class Information, 1974 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Roman Seminar (Box 50, Folder 6-7)
  - Romanesque Architecture Seminar, 1975 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Romanesque Seminar (Box 50, Folder 9-11)
  - Selected Readings Core Source, Fall 1991 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Skyscraper Seminar, 1980 (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Tresco Art Seminar (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Visual Arts in Fourteenth Century Italy, 1979 (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Writing Course Instruction, 1988 (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - World Cities Class Information, 1990-2000 (Box 50, Folder 17)
  - World Cities Source Book (Box 50, Folder 18)
  - World Cities Syllabus (Box 50, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, 1973-2010; VIII.
  This series contains incoming and outgoing correspondence from throughout Dr. Toker's career as a professor and author. These records also include letters from his time as president of the Society of Architectural Historians. Some correspondence is in Italian.
  - Personal Correspondence, 1978-2010; 1.
    The Personal Correspondence subseries is made up of personal letters to and from Dr. Toker and family, friends and colleagues discussing a variety of topics from 1978 to 2010. This subseries also includes several journals kept by Dr. Toker during the 1970s.
    - Personal Correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 50, Folder 20)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 50, Folder 21)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1980 (Box 50, Folder 22)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1980-1982 (Box 50, Folder 23)
    - Personal Correspondence, September, 1981- August 1983 (Box 50, Folder 24)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1984-1987 (Box 50, Folder 25)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1987-1994 (Box 50, Folder 26)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1987-1994 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1995-1999 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1995-2000 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1996-2001 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Personal Correspondence, 2002 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Personal Correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Personal Correspondence, 2003 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Personal Correspondence, 2003-2004 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Personal Correspondence, 2004-2005 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Personal Correspondence, 2005-2006 (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - Personal Correspondence, 2006-2007 (Box 51, Folder 13)
    - Personal Correspondence, 2008-2010 (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Professional Correspondence, 1973-2016; 2.